Finding Aid for Constance E. Cumbey papers, 1920-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Constance E. Cumbey papers 1920-2004 1980-1999
Cumbey, Constance E.
04101 Aa 2
Attorney, student and investigator of different cults and cult activities, primarily focusing on the New Age Movement; published writings, collected topical files; cassette sound recordings, and videotapes.
87 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was received from Constance Cumbey (donor no. 9446 ) in various accessions, 2004 and 2007..
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Constance Elizabeth Cumbey, nee Butler, was born 29 February 1944 in Fort Wayne, Indiana. Cumbey was raised as a Seventh Day Adventist and as an adult converted to the Baptist faith. She completed her pre-law studies at Michigan State University and Wayne State University. In 1975 she received her juris doctor degree from Detroit College of Law. Constance Cumbey's professional activities include working as a legislative analyst for William A. Ryan, speaker of the Michigan House of Representatives, from 1969 to 1970, being employed as a consultant to the Governmental Efficiency Subcommittee of the Appropriations Committee for the Michigan State Senate, serving as corresponding secretary and treasurer of the National Association of Women Lawyers, and acting as chairperson of the Family Law Committee of the General Practice Section of the American Bar Association. She has continuously served by appointment on the Public Advisory Committee of the State Bar of Michigan since 1978. Cumbey has been active in the litigation, criminal, family law, and general practice sections of the American Bar Association. In 2003 she was appointed to serve a three year term to plan future State Bar meetings by the State Bar of Michigan. From 1992 to 2004 Constance Cumbey hosted Law Talk, a call-in radio program on a Christian radio station.
Between the years 1981 and 1988 Constance Cumbey ceased her law practice and dedicated her life to investigating the New Age Movement. Cumbey's The Hidden Dangers of the Rainbow, published in 1983, was a best-selling Christian book and was one of the first works to criticize the movement from a fundamentalist Christian perspective. A sequel, A Planned Deception: The Staging of a New Age Messiah, was published in 1985. She also circulated a newsletter titled Constance Cumbey's New Age Monitor.
The Constance Cumbey collection consists of her publications, research files and other material related to her investigations of alleged connections between New Age cults and the New World Order and various politicians, organizations and institutions. There are also files documenting her interest in Christian fundamentalism and prominent evangelists and their ties to cults. The collection has been divided into three series: Topical Files (three subseries), Personal Files, and Other Media.
Subjects:
Cumbey, Constance E.; New Age movement.; Occultism.; United States--Religion--1960-
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Cumbey, Constance E.; New Age movement.; Occultism.; Solana, Javier.; Burroughs, Elizabeth.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Cumbey, Constance E.; New Age movement.; Occultism.
Genre Terms:
CD-ROMs.; Videotapes.; Audiocassettes.; Sound recordings.
- Topical Files
  Topical Files makes up the bulk of the collection with three subseries of files, each arranged alphabetically, but kept separate because of different dates of accessions.
  - Group 1
    This first of three Topical Files subseries has been designated Group 1 (16 linear feet; bulk dates 1985-1995) and consists of a wide variety of collected material on the New Age Movement. Due to the success of her first book The Hidden Dangers of the Rainbow Constance Cumbey established a wide correspondence network which enabled her to build an impressive collection of ephemeral materials and independent publications -- material which is sometimes referred to as "gray literature" or "fugitive literature." The series contains general information about the New Age Movement such as pamphlets and magazines regarding globalization, alternative religions, spirituality, alternative lifestyles, technology, Afrocentrism, feminism, and foreign politics. There is also information on known New Age leaders Benjamin Creme and the Maitreya movement, Robert Muller and AD 2000 movement, and Bubba Free John and the Free Communion Church. A strength of this series is the large amount of information about education in Michigan and how the New Age Movement may have influenced the creation of new educational measures such as the Malcolm X Academy in Detroit, the Michigan Model, outcome based education, and home schooling.
    - Abortion 1990-1995, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Acton Institute 1994-2002 (Box 1)
    - AD 2000 Movement, 1994-1996, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Adopt-A-People Clearinghouse 1995 (Box 1)
    - Adultery 1990 (Box 1)
    - African-American Anti-Semitism 1990-1996 (Box 1)
    - Afro-Americans 1990-1993 (Box 1)
    - Afro-Centric Curriculum 1990-1994 (Box 1)
    - Afrocentrism
      - 1990-1998, 3 folders (Box 1)
      - MoBetter News Newspaper 1991 (Box 1)
    - African History 1990 (Box 1)
    - AIDS 1987-1993 (Box 1)
    - Aid and Abet Police Newsletter 1992 (Box 1)
    - Albionic Research 1984 (Box 1)
    - Alcoholics Anonymous 1989 (Box 1)
    - Alien Abduction 1985-1994 (Box 1)
    - Alinsky, Saul and Community Organizing 1997 (Box 1)
    - Alliance Defense Fund, Inc. 1994-1997 (Box 1)
    - Alternative Living, Ann Arbor, MI 1989 (Box 1)
    - America 2000, 1992 (Box 1)
    - American Bar Association-Tort and Religion 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    - American Center for Law and Justice 1996 (Box 1)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) 1986-1992 (Box 1)
    - American Colony in Jerusalem 1997 (Box 1)
    - American Family Association (Box 1)
    - American Freedom Coalition 1988 (Box 1)
    - American Legislative Exchange Council (ALEC) 1973-1995 (Box 1)
    - American Liberty Association 1993 (Box 1)
    - Anarchists, National Security Anarchists Newsletter 1991 (Box 1)
    - Anarchy 1976-1992 (Box 1)
    - Angels 1995-2000 (Box 1)
    - Animal Rights Activism 1988-1993 (Box 1)
    - Anti-Catholicism (Box 1)
    - Anti-Christian 1946-1989 (Box 1)
    - Anti-Cult 1997 (Box 1)
    - Anti-Defamation League (ADL) Reports 1987-1992 (Box 1)
    - Anti-Free Masonry (Box 1)
    - Anti-Fundamentalist 1981-1994 (Box 1)
    - Anti-Government 1996 (Box 1)
    - Anti-Mormon 1990-1995 (Box 1)
    - Anti-New Age 1986-2001, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Anti-New Age-Light Warriors 1992-1995 (Box 2)
    - Anti-New Age-Peterson, Willy 1996-1997 (Box 2)
    - Anti-New World Order 1992 (Box 2)
    - Antipas Ministries 1996 (Box 2)
    - Anti-Pornography 1990 (Box 2)
    - Anti-Scientology 1991 (Box 2)
    - Anti-Semitism 1990-1998 (Box 2)
    - Apostasy (Box 2)
    - Applied Manufacturing Conference 2002 (Box 2)
    - Archbishop Desmond Tutu 1989 (Box 2)
    - Arizona's Spiritual Movements 1989-1991 (Box 2)
    - Army 1994 (Box 2)
    - Aryan Nations (Box 2)
    - Astronomy 1992 (Box 2)
    - Attention Deficit Disorder and Hyperactivity (Box 2)
    - Baca Ashrams (Box 2)
    - Baha'i Faith 1989 (Box 2)
    - Bakker, Jim 1989 (Box 2)
    - Banner Ministries-Mainstream Newsletter 1993-1997 (Box 2)
    - The Banner of Life Newspaper 1924 (Box 2)
    - The Baptist Church 1985-2000 (Box 2)
    - Baseline Essays: African and African-American Contributions to Science and Technology (Box 2)
    - Biblical Discipleship Ministries 1994 (Box 2)
    - Biblical Fundamentalism-Foundation Magazine 1990-1992 (Box 2)
    - Bible Prophecy News 1992-1995 (Box 2)
    - Bible Versions 1995 (Box 2)
    - Birth Control (Box 2)
    - Black Extremists (Box 2)
    - Black History Month 1993-1994 (Box 2)
    - Black-Jewish Relations 1993-1994 (Box 2)
    - Black Muslim Movement 1995 (Box 2)
    - Black Nationalists 1994 (Box 2)
    - Blair, Tony 2002 (Box 2)
    - Blood Oath 1996 (Box 2)
    - B'nai B'rith Society 1996 (Box 2)
    - Bob Larson's Ministry 1993 (Box 2)
    - Bold Truth Press 1992 (Box 2)
    - Born Again Believers 1992 (Box 2)
    - Bread for the World Christian Movement 1998 (Box 2)
    - Buddhism 1994 (Box 2)
    - Bush, George and New Age Ideology 1988-1992 (Box 2)
    - Capital Punishment 1992 (Box 2)
    - Capital Research Center 1989-1991 (Box 2)
    - Cashless Society 1994-1999 (Box 2)
    - Cathars (Box 2)
    - Cathedral of St. John the Divine (Box 2)
    - Catholic Alliance 1996 (Box 2)
    - Catholic Education 1990-1995 (Box 2)
    - Catholic Support 1986-1992 (Box 2)
    - Catholic Mysticism 1992 (Box 2)
    - Catholic New Age 1991-1998 (Box 2)
    - Catholicism
      - Legatus Foundation 1996 (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous 1990-2003, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - Catholicism and Child Abuse 1991-1993 (Box 2)
    - Catholicism and the Holocaust 1989-1994 (Box 2)
    - The Cell Church 1995-1996 (Box 2)
    - Center for Holistic Energy Management and Applied Metaphysics 1986 (Box 2)
    - Center for the Dances of Universal Peace 1988-1989 (Box 2)
    - Center for World Mission 1995 (Box 2)
    - Centering Prayer Ministry 1988 (Box 2)
    - Central European Bank 1988 (Box 2)
    - Change Agents-"A Guide to Innovation in Education" 1970 (Box 2)
    - Charismatic Movement 1989-1994 (Box 2)
    - Charter Schools 1993 (Box 2)
    - Chemical Abuse Resolution Lies in Education (Project CHARLIE) 1988 (Box 2)
    - Chemical Weapons 1996 (Box 2)
    - Christian Bible Students (Box 2)
    - Christian Coalition 1991-2001 (Box 2)
    - Christian Country 1995 (Box 2)
    - Christian Crusade Church-Christian Vanguard Newsletter 1983 (Box 3)
    - Christian Crusade Ministries 2001 (Box 3)
    - Christian Economic Values 1989-1995 (Box 3)
    - Christian Education 1974-1996 (Box 3)
    - Christian Fundamentalists used by Conspirators 1989 (Box 3)
    - Christian Identity Movement 1994 (Box 3)
    - Christian Information Bureau (CIB) Bulletin 1987-1991 (Box 3)
    - Christian Intelligence Alert 1992 (Box 3)
    - Christian Intelligence Journal 1994 (Box 3)
    - Christian Music 1994-1997 (Box 3)
    - Christian News Network 1982 (Box 3)
    - Christian Patriots-Jeffrey Baker 1994 (Box 3)
    - Christian Reconstructionism 1990-1995 (Box 3)
    - Christian Rescue Effort for the Emancipation of Dissidents (CREED) Newsletter 1987-1988 (Box 3)
    - Christian Response to the New Age Movement 1990-1991 (Box 3)
    - Christian Sons of Liberty 1992 (Box 3)
    - Christianity
      - Coalition on Revival 1986 (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous 1982-1999, 8 folders (Box 3)
    - Christianity and the Internet 1995 (Box 3)
    - Christianity Today Magazine 1994 (Box 3)
    - Church and State Issues 1985-1989 (Box 3)
    - Church of the Living Word 1990 (Box 3)
    - Civil Rights Movement 1996 (Box 3)
    - Coalition of Revival 1994 (Box 3)
    - Committee to Restore the Constitution 1993 (Box 3)
    - Common Boundary Pamphlet (Box 3)
    - Communications Era Task Force 1983 (Box 3)
    - Communism 1989-1990 (Box 3)
    - Communism in the Classroom 1989 (Box 3)
    - Concentration Camps 1993-1994 (Box 3)
    - Concerned Christian Association of Michigan (CCAM) 1992 (Box 3)
    - Concerned Women for America Organization 1986 (Box 3)
    - Constitutional Convention 1991-1993 (Box 3)
    - Control of the Masses-'Silent Weapons for Quiet Wars Programming Manual' (Box 3)
    - Council for National Policy (CNP) 1988-2000 (Box 3)
    - Council on Biblical Manhood and Womanhood (CBMW) 1995 (Box 3)
    - Council on Foreign Relations (CFR) 1998 (Box 3)
    - Course in Miracles 1986 (Box 3)
    - Cousteau Society (Box 3)
    - Creation Centered Spirituality 1992 (Box 3)
    - Creative Education Foundation 1990 (Box 3)
    - Creme, Benjamin (Box 3)
    - C.S. Lewis Institute 1995 (Box 3)
    - Cult Awareness Network Conference 1985-1986 (Box 3)
    - Cults
      - Children 1978-1988 (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous 1984-2001, 3 folders (Box 4)
      - Mormonism 1988 (Box 4)
    - The Dad's Foundation 1992 (Box 4)
    - Dalai Lama 1994 (Box 4)
    - Development Education Association 1995 (Box 4)
    - Dicksons Bookstore, 'A Closer Look' Newsletter 1992 (Box 4)
    - Discernment Ministries Inc 1990-2004 (Box 4)
    - Discernment Ministries-Alabama 1995-1996 (Box 4)
    - 'Distant Drums' Newsletter 1982-1992 (Box 4)
    - Divorce 1997 (Box 4)
    - Drug Awareness Resistance Education (DARE) 1994-1995 (Box 4)
    - DuPont Company and New Age 1990-1992 (Box 4)
    - Earth Action Group 1995 (Box 4)
    - Earth Education 1992 (Box 4)
    - Earth Summit 1992-1997 (Box 4)
    - Earth Transition-The Phoenix Express Newsletter 1991 (Box 4)
    - Earth Worship 1990-2002, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Ecology as Nazism 1994 (Box 4)
    - Ecumenism 1964-1995 (Box 4)
    - Education 1976-2000, 5 folders (Box 4)
    - Education and Commercialism 1995 (Box 4)
    - Education
      - Critical Thinking 1988 (Box 4)
      - Detroit, MI 1992-1993, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Detroit, MI 1992-1993, 1 folders (Box 5)
      - Michigan 1989-1994, 6 folders (Box 5)
      - Michigan Alliance of Families 1994 (Box 5)
      - The Michigan Model 1991-1993 (Box 5)
      - National Educational Longitudinal Study of 8th Graders 1988 (Box 5)
      - Policy on Character 1996 (Box 5)
      - School Based Clinics (SBC's) 1986 (Box 5)
      - School to Work Plan in Michigan 1994-1996 (Box 5)
      - Skinnerian International Curriculum 1985 (Box 5)
      - Steiner, Rudolf (Box 5)
      - TI-IN Network and Distance Education 1990-1992 (Box 5)
      - United Nations Educational Scientific Organization (UNESCO) 1990 (Box 5)
      - Williamsburg Charter Foundation 1990 (Box 5)
    - Education and Technology 1990 (Box 5)
    - Education Bills 1992 (Box 5)
    - Educators for Social Responsibility 1990 (Box 5)
    - Educational Research Institute 1992 (Box 5)
    - Einhorn, Ira (The Unicorn) (Box 5)
    - Einstein, Albert 1955, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Election 1992 (Box 5)
    - England, New Age Bulletin 1991 (Box 5)
    - Environmental Law 1980-1996 (Box 5)
    - Environmental Movement 1989-1995, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - The Erikson Institute 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - Esotericists 1954 (Box 5)
    - Eugenics 1997 (Box 5)
    - European Issue 1992 (Box 5)
    - Eurythmy 1990 (Box 5)
    - Euthanasia 1991-2001, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Evangelical Ministries to New Religions Group 2001 (Box 6)
    - Evangelicals 1986-1996 (Box 6)
    - Executive Intelligence Review (EIR) 1993 (Box 6)
    - Extraterrestrials-Unicus Magazine 1992 (Box 6)
    - Extremism 1993 (Box 6)
    - False Memory Syndrome 1991-2002 (Box 6)
    - Falwell, Jerry 1983 (Box 6)
    - Fantasy (Box 6)
    - Farrakhan, Louis 1985-1995 (Box 6)
    - Fascism 1994 (Box 6)
    - Fatima Religious Movement 1992-1996 (Box 6)
    - Fellowship in Prayer Newsletter 1997 (Box 6)
    - Feminism 1992-2000 (Box 6)
    - Feminist New Age 1989 (Box 6)
    - Financial Advice-Gary North (Box 6)
    - Focus on the Family 1995-1996 (Box 6)
    - Foreign Policy 2003 (Box 6)
    - The Fourteenth Amendment 1994 (Box 6)
    - The Free Communion Church and Bubba Free John 1978 (Box 6)
    - Free World Research Report 1993 (Box 6)
    - Freemasonry
      - Miscellaneous 1993 (Box 6)
      - 'Empire State Mason' Newsletter 1988-1989 (Box 6)
    - Fuller Theological Seminary 1990 (Box 6)
    - Futurism (Box 6)
    - Gaia Theory 1989-1998 (Box 6)
    - Gangs 1988 (Box 6)
    - The Gateways Institute 1990 (Box 6)
    - 'The General Practitioner' Newsletter 1992 (Box 6)
    - Gender Bias 1990 (Box 6)
    - Gingrich, Newt 1974-1996 (Box 6)
    - Global Education 1988-1993 (Box 6)
    - Global Energy Grid 1987 (Box 6)
    - Global Evangelization 1990-1996 (Box 6)
    - Global Governance 1995 (Box 6)
    - Globalism 1995 (Box 6)
    - Globalism and Apostasy 1993 (Box 6)
    - Global Religion 1995 (Box 6)
    - Goals 2000, 1994 (Box 6)
    - The Goddess Movement (Box 6)
    - Gore, Al 1991-2000 (Box 6)
    - Government in Detroit and Southeast Michigan-Observation Balloon Newsletter 1992 (Box 6)
    - Graham, Billy 1989-2000 (Box 6)
    - The Great Invocation, Lucis Trust 1922-1997 (Box 6)
    - Greenpeace 1990-1993 (Box 6)
    - Gulf War
      - Miscellaneous 1991, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Hal Lindsey Ministries 1984 (Box 6)
    - 'Have a Good Day' Newsletter 1995-1996 (Box 6)
    - Health Care 1991-2001 (Box 6)
    - Hermeticism 1995 (Box 6)
    - Hillsdale College 1989 (Box 6)
    - Hinduism (Box 6)
    - Hitler, Adolph (Box 6)
    - Holland-Environmental Movement 1989 (Box 6)
    - Holistic Health (Box 6)
    - Home Instruction Program for Pre-School Youngsters (HIPPY) 1989 (Box 6)
    - Home Schooling 1989-1995 (Box 6)
    - Homosexuality 1987-1998 (Box 6)
    - Hope International 1989-1996 (Box 6)
    - Hospice and 'Do not Resuscitate' 1994 (Box 6)
    - Hubbard Dianetics Foundation 1988 (Box 6)
    - Human Functioning 1992 (Box 6)
    - Humanism 1989-1993 (Box 7)
    - Human Life International 1991-2001, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Illiteracy 1989 (Box 7)
    - Immigration 1994 (Box 7)
    - Incarceration-Restoration House of America Organization 1999 (Box 7)
    - Infectious Diseases 1994 (Box 7)
    - Indonesia 1997-1998 (Box 7)
    - Institute of Cultural Affairs 1991-1992 (Box 7)
    - Institute of Natural Health Sciences 1990 (Box 7)
    - Institute of Noetic Sciences 1989-1995 (Box 7)
    - Iowans for Tax Relief 1987-1991 (Box 7)
    - Israel 1989-2003 (Box 7)
    - Jack Van Impe Ministries International (Box 7)
    - Japan 1989 (Box 7)
    - Jerusalem 1991 (Box 7)
    - The Jesuits (Box 7)
    - Jesus, CEO Foundation 1999 (Box 7)
    - Jews for Jesus 1989 (Box 7)
    - Jewish New Age 1988-1993 (Box 7)
    - Jewish Organizations 1997 (Box 7)
    - Jewish Telegraphic Agency Newsletter 1994-1995 (Box 7)
    - Jimmy Swaggart Ministries 1986 (Box 7)
    - Joe Stumpf Ministries 2001 (Box 7)
    - John Birch Society 1989-1997 (Box 7)
    - Journal of Historical Review 1993 (Box 7)
    - Jubilee 2000, 1984-1999 (Box 7)
    - Judaism 1920, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Judaism and the Messiah 1992-1993 (Box 7)
    - Kabbalah (Box 7)
    - Kenneth Copeland Ministries 1993 (Box 7)
    - Kevorkian, Jack 1990-1998, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Kevorkian, Jack-Legal Cases
      - Gale vs. Mills 1994 (Box 7)
      - Nicol vs. Cumbey 1994 (Box 7)
      - Nicol vs. Mills 1995 (Box 7)
    - The Kibbo Kift Foundation 1998 (Box 7)
    - Kids Peace (Box 7)
    - King, Coretta Scott. Religious Conflicts 1989 (Box 7)
    - King James Herald Newsletter 1996 (Box 7)
    - Kinseyian Philosophy 1994 (Box 7)
    - Kwanzaa 1972-1993 (Box 7)
    - Labor Unions 1992 (Box 7)
    - LaRouche, Lyndon H. 1981-1993, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Lazaris 1989 (Box 7)
    - The Laughing Man Institute 1978-1985 (Box 7)
    - The Laughter Movement 1990-1995 (Box 7)
    - Lawrence Coalition for Peace and Justice (LCPJ) 1989 (Box 7)
    - Legal Positivism 1996 (Box 7)
    - Lewis, C.S. (Box 7)
    - Liberal Catholic Church 1996 (Box 8)
    - Libertarians 1989-1990 (Box 8)
    - 'Liberty' Magazine 1992 (Box 8)
    - Libraries 1989 (Box 8)
    - Light of the City Ministry (Box 8)
    - The Light Warrior Newsletter 1995-1996 (Box 8)
    - 'Little Cloud Report' Newsletter 1994-1996 (Box 8)
    - Living Truth Ministries-'Flashpoint' Newsletter 1990-1998 (Box 8)
    - Llewellyn Publications 1983-1990, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Lovins, Amory and his "soft path" 1992 (Box 8)
    - Lubatcher Rebbe Movement 1990-1992 (Box 8)
    - Lucis Trust Foundation (Box 8)
    - Maharishi Heaven on Earth Development Company 1990 (Box 8)
    - Maitreya as Christ-Masters of Wisdom 1980-2001, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Malcolm X 1992-1993 (Box 8)
    - The Manifest Sons of God 1977-1986 (Box 8)
    - March for Jesus (Box 8)
    - Valtoria Research Center 1993-1994 (Box 8)
    - Marian Movement 1989 (Box 8)
    - Marrs, Texe 1991-1993 (Box 8)
    - Marshall, Catherine 1987 (Box 8)
    - Martin, Malachi 1965-1996 (Box 8)
    - McAlvany Intelligence Advisor 1989 (Box 8)
    - McAuley Institute 1999 (Box 8)
    - Meditation 1985-1995 (Box 8)
    - The Medjugorie Movement 1992-2004 (Box 8)
    - Melanin Mind Enhancement 1990 (Box 8)
    - The Men's Movement 1992-2001 (Box 8)
    - Mephistopheles 1992 (Box 8)
    - The Meta Church 1994 (Box 8)
    - Metro Omaha Right to Life 1992 (Box 8)
    - Metropolitan Alliance of Congregations 1997 (Box 8)
    - Mexico-Religious Freedom 1992-1994 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Alliance of Families (Box 8)
    - Michigan Committee for Freedom 1990 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Education Assessment Program (MEAP) 1988 (Box 8)
    - The Midnight Cry Newsletter 1992-1993 (Box 9)
    - Miles, Christy 2001 (Box 9)
    - Militia Groups 1994-1998 (Box 9)
    - Militia Groups-Michigan 1997 (Box 9)
    - Millennium and Y2K 1998-1999 (Box 9)
    - The Million Man March, 1995 (Box 9)
    - Miracles 1992-1995 (Box 9)
    - Missionaries/Missions 2002 (Box 9)
    - Mormonism (Box 9)
    - Moral Values Education 1987 (Box 9)
    - Mormons and Mormonism 1994-1995 (Box 9)
    - Mormonism, 'The Evangel' Newsletter 1992 (Box 9)
    - Mormonism, 'The Inner Circle' Newsletter 1989-1993 (Box 9)
    - Mother Jones Magazine (Box 9)
    - Mount Zion Temple 1989 (Box 9)
    - Mystique of Big Sur, Arizona 1998 (Box 9)
    - Nation of Islam 1987-1999 (Box 9)
    - National Center for Fathering 1994 (Box 9)
    - National Coalition of Free Men 1994 (Box 9)
    - National Congress for Men and Children 1992 (Box 9)
    - National Congress for Men and Children: Accusations of Sexual Abuse in Custody Disputes 1992 (Box 9)
    - National Education Association (NEA) 1985-1992 (Box 9)
    - National European American Society 1992 (Box 9)
    - National Taxpayers Union 1991-1992 (Box 9)
    - Natural Disasters 1990-2001 (Box 9)
    - The Natural Law Party 1992 (Box 9)
    - The Nature Conservancy-Desert Tortoise Conservation Center (Box 9)
    - Nature Religion 1995 (Box 9)
    - Navigators 1994 (Box 9)
    - Nazi and Nazism 1986-2002 (Box 9)
    - Nazi's and United States Support 1988-1995 (Box 9)
    - Negative Population Growth, Inc. 1991-1997 (Box 9)
    - Neuro-Linguistic Programming 1989-1994 (Box 9)
    - New Age Adversary Bulletin 1993-1997 (Box 9)
    - New Age
      - Arts Club Online Chat Transcripts 1991 (Box 9)
      - Bandler, Richard 1989 (Box 9)
      - Bible Versions 1981-1990 (Box 9)
      - Bulletin Newsletter 1990-1992 (Box 9)
      - Contact: The Phoenix Project Newspaper 1993, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Divorce 1992 (Box 9)
      - Eastern Religion 1985-2002 (Box 9)
      - Education 1988-1998, 3 folders (Box 9)
      - Free Masons 1996 (Box 10)
      - Health Care 1984-1990 (Box 10)
      - Images (Box 10)
      - Management Training 1953-2003 (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous 1983-2002, 11 folders (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous 1983-2002, 5 folders (Box 11)
      - Music 1994-1995 (Box 11)
      - Native Americans 1994-2002 (Box 11)
      - New Age Journal 1993 (Box 11)
      - The New Technology of Achievement (NLP) (Box 11)
      - North Carolina 1997 (Box 11)
      - Related Legislation 1961-1989 (Box 11)
      - Religious Control 1994-1995 (Box 11)
      - Reverend Matthew Fox 1990-1996 (Box 11)
      - Technology 1989-1995 (Box 11)
      - Welfare Grants 1992 (Box 11)
    - New Age Monitor Newsletter 1986-1991 (Box 11)
    - New Age Religion-Knoxville, TN 1998 (Box 11)
    - New Age Review 1994 (Box 11)
    - The New American Magazine 1998 (Box 11)
    - New Christian Activism Movement-'Scoreboard' Newsletter 1989 (Box 11)
    - New European Order 1990-1995 (Box 11)
    - The New Federalist 1989 (Box 11)
    - New Life 2000-World Evangelization 1988-1995 (Box 11)
    - New Order 1991 (Box 11)
    - New Wave Theology 1987-1991 (Box 11)
    - New World Order (NWO) 1951-1997 (Box 11)
    - New World Order Education (Box 11)